Ethan Post

DevOps Engineer

DevOps Engineer with almost 3 years of experience in the world of AWS and with 2 years of experiences previously spent as a Software Engineer. I have plenty of exposure in designing and streamlining playbooks in Ansible with a recent love of Terraform; dipping my toes in kubernetes. I also have plenty of exposure working on docker containers and automating with pipelines in Gitlab. I have found that I love working in the cloud and keeping up with the fast pace nature that this industry brings.



Personal Info

Address

1156 Grand Ave Astoria, Oregon 97103

Phone

(712) 461-2593

Email

ethancpost@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/maker2413



Skills

Infrastructure-as-code Containers CI/CD Documentation Training others



Software

AWS Ansible Bash/Zsh/Fish C/C++ Cloudformation CloudWatch Docker Gitlab CI/Jenkins Grafana Python Postgres/Mysql/Hana ■■■□□□□ Terraform 変 変 変 数



Education

Dakota State University

(Aug 2014 - May 2017)

Bachelor's in Computer Science Minoring in Computer Information Systems

GPA: 3.302



Work Experience

DevOps Engineer

Threatconnect Inc - Arlington, VA [Remote] (July 2019 - Current)

- Was Team lead of a group designated to redesign and expand our Terraform repository to encapsulate infrastructure that was previously managed through our Ansible Repos.
- Supported over 100 clients in our cloud environment around the clock and even worked in our weekly rotating on call schedule.
- Lead an effort to redesign our Ansible code base into separated repositories for each role to implement automated testing on our Ansible roles.
- Began work on moving our ELK Stack and Grafana monitoring cluster into EKS managed by using Terraform and Helm charts.
- Helped design Docker images and our CI files in GItlab after moving away from BitBucket.

DevOps Engineer

Earth Resources Observation and Science (EROS) Center Sioux Falls, SD (May 2018 - June 2019)

- Managed the Jenkins Server in our AWS environment and codified it with ansible including auto scaling EC2 workers.
- Built many ansible playbooks to build and configure AWS instances, AMIs, and Grafana dashboards.
- Got experience working in the agile development lifecycle with daily scrums and weekly sprints.
- Gained knowledge of linux system skills like scripting (python and bash), small bits of system admin skills (cron jobs and package management), and virtualization through docker containers.
- Was given the responsibility to train, teach, and manage some of our new hires.

Software Engineer

EROS Sioux Falls, SD (May 2017 - May 2018)

- Obtained Experience taking part in meetings and talking to the government customers.
- Was the solo developer for the Scheduling system used at EROS.
- Gained large amounts of experience in C/C++ including working with the Qt graphics library.
- Learned how to manage databases with MySQL and PostgresQL.

Software Engineer Intern

EROS Sioux Falls, SD (December 2016 - May 2017)

- Learned how to use SVN and Git.
- Developed Experience in the waterfall development life cycle.
- Acquired the skill of writing and reviewing documentation in Confluence.
- Learned how to write and work on tickets in JIRA.